MUHAMAD ARIFFUDIN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Johor Baharu, Johor | +60 11 1067 3172 | muhamad-ariffudin.github.io muhamadariffudin49@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/muhamad-ariffudin/

PROFILE SUMMARY

Passionate UIUX Developer with a degree in Software Engineering. With 4 years of experience in the industry. I am a quick learner who is curious and enjoys solving problems with the best solution. I work well in teams and am eager to apply my knowledge and experience to your company and enhance my professional career.

PROFESSIONAL SKILL

- UI & UX Design, Product Design
- HTML5, CSS, JavaScript
- PHP, JAVA, ASP.NET
- Laravel, React JS, React Native
- Kotlin, Swift, Flutter
- SQL, My SQL, Firebase
- Wordpress, Webflow, Shopify

TECHNICAL SKILL

- Visual Studio Code, Visual studio,
- Net Bean, Android Studio, X Code
- Git Hub, Git Lab, Trello, Slack
- Photoshop, Illustrate, Premiere pro
- Adobe XD, Flgma, Sketch, Miro, InVision
- Wireframe, Prototyping, Research, Usability testing
- SEO, Google analytic, Google & Facebook Ads

EDUCATION

BSc (Hons) in Software Engineering

Asia Pacific University of Technology & Innovation

CGPA: 2.65/4

Dip in Information Technology (Programming)

Polytechnic Balik Pulau

CGPA: 2.86/4

2018 - 2020

2015 - 2017

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software UI/UX Developer [Full Time]

Alphacore Technology Sdn. Bhd. [Kuala Lumpur]

Dec 2021 - Nov 2022

- Designed and developed a HRMS system (AlphaDash) using the Laravel PHP framework and ReactJS. Actively participated in the entire software development process, from planning to implementation.
- Collaborated with 15 cross-functional teams including business analysts, product managers, designers, and developers to ensure successful execution of development and designs.
- Used tools like Adobe Illustrate, Figma, Miro, and Sketch to convey ideas and design concepts through wireframes and drawings. Improved user experience by conducting usability testings, identifying UX issues and proposing design recommendations.
- Contributed to create the frontend and API for the HRMS system, troubleshooted and resolved issues, and performed database maintenance.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer [Full Time]

Sep 2020 - Nov 2021

SRG Asia Pacific Sdn. Bhd. [Kuala Lumpur]

- Collaborated with a team of 10 developers to create a contact center dialer application with a PHP and MySQL database using Agile methodology.
- Supported and maintained the call center dialer software (vici_dial) with over 3,000+ staff during critical periods for any troubleshooting. To ensure that the software met user requirements and any code issues.
- Created well-designed, tested code that follows best practices for website development, including responsive design, also made report pages and user interfaces that show data from back-end services and databases, which increased staff productivity by 30%.

Web Developer [Contract]

May 2020 - Aug 2020

Samurai Paint Sdn. Bhd. [Johor Bahru]

- revamped the (Samurai Paint) website and mobile apps to improve the overall experience by performing user interviews to understand the learners mindset, crafting personas and a customer journey map, and conducting heuristic evaluation and competitive analysis to ensure that the redesign met the users needs.
- collaborated in developing the User Interface and coding for websites, managed maintenance, updates, expansions, and scaling to ensure optimal performance by implemented a Docker technology to guarantee seamless accessibility across different computer systems and browsers.

Web UI/UX Developer [Full Time]

Jun 2019 - May 2020

George Healthcare Sdn. Bhd. [Kuala Lumpur]

- Developed an eCommerce website, (Healtopedia) a healthcare system using PHP and MySQL, which had 6,000+ monthly visitors. Collaboration with teams to ensure that the new feature meets the demands of customers and the company's aims.
- Collaborate in the design and improvement of overall UI/UX websites utilising tools such as Miro and Figma to design and research that increased the platforms System Usability Scale from 66.9 to 87.5 through usability testing and iterations.
- Websites were improved by taking into account client demands and feedback, as well as doing research, testing, and data analysis. Planned and executed large projects, delivering excellent outcomes that exceeded customer expectations.

Web UI/UX Developer [Full Time]

May 2017 - Apr 2018

Web Creative Solutions Sdn. Bhd. [Johor Bahru]

- Contribute in the HRMSystem and the e-commerce project, resolve issues, do quality assurance testing on the system, and work on the front and back ends of the system, as well as the UI/UX.
- Collaborate with internal teams to develop, design, and implement solutions. Aided in the implementation of payment applications, which are currently utilised by all of the 29 company's e-commerce clients sites.
- Delivered high-quality, efficient solutions that fulfilled the client's requirements and enhanced their entire business procedures, resulting in a 25% increase in company revenue.

Web Developer [Internship]

Feb 2017 - Apr 2017

DreamSpace Sdn. Bhd. [Johor Bahru]

- Participate in developing and enhancing existing system modules, and actively participated in SCRUM sessions to gain a deep understanding of the software development life cycle.
- Worked closely with the client during the design and implementation phases to ensure that the final product satisfies the requirements.